Sanjay Shrestha

DesOps, UX Architect, HFI CUA™



http://sanjayshrestha.com http:// behance.net/shresthasans https://www.linkedin.com/in/shresthasans https://github.com/shresthasans http://jsfiddle.net/user/shresthasans http://codepen.io/shresthasans

> dziner.sanjay@gmail.com sanzaysan (skype) (+977) 9849645811 (mobile)

ABOUT ME

Full-stack designer, certified HFI CUA™ and a Nepalese, have eight plus (8+) years of experience in UX/UI Design and UI Development, been with start-ups and medium to large tech companies, created huge impact on leading product definition and development, improving user-experience in B2B and B2C software products.

SKILLS

- Specialties: User Centered Analysis and Design Approach, Agile Software development process
 Clean/Modern UI Design, CSS₃ Animation, On-Page SEO, Power-point
 Presentation, Designing in the Browser, Accessibility, Usability, Project
 Management, Team Lead, A/B Testing
- Data Analysis: FullStory, VWO, Google Analytics
- PM Tools: Axosoft, Basecamp, Asana, Jira
- Graphics Software: Sketch, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Balsamiq, Axure RP, Moqups
- Languages: (X)HTML 4/5, CSS2/3, Sass/SCSS, LESS, JavaScript
- Dev Frameworks: Material Design, Bootstrap, Foundation, jQuery, jQueryUI, jQuery Mobile
- Web Dev tools: Grunt, Gulp, YEOMAN, Bower, Jade, Sublime Text3
- VCS: Git, SVN, TFS
- CLI: CMD, Terminal

SELECTED PROJECTS

UX (Research and Process)

- Invoice App
 - https://www.dropbox.com/sh/a81fzkpgvcoxr4n/AABPZXOrRLLD07rUnjLyuMI1a?dl=0
- Smart Class Schedule
 - https://www.dropbox.com/sh/m46kce406xkczj3/AAD0QWZW_pTNTcZTC8_cZ4FVa?dl=0
- HR Dashboard
 - https://www.dropbox.com/sh/eifd3773uzrrotq/AACpl0wvMcBgAwl4fhsszSHva?dl=0

Nepal PMO

https://www.dropbox.com/sh/516avmwo5vovn2u/AADVl0xVMyAY4O8dCxkT667Na?dl=0 http://xgs5oj.axshare.com/ (Wireframe)

Bifrost

https://www.dropbox.com/sh/u2jiiur1br72bmo/AABLWl1oj9G1fGqDCMMB5Cxga?dl=o

Zero Meetings

https://www.dropbox.com/sh/usglq2lajw96207/AACUqU5LujY4dWHSf3d9mv8ia?dl=0 http://epi8im.axshare.com (Wireframe)

Persona (Presentation)

- http://sanjayshrestha.com/presentations/SberBankInRoomAssistanceLoan.ppsx
- http://sanjayshrestha.com/presentations/TacomaPublicSchools.ppsx

Mobile App/Website Projects (Design/UIDevelopment)

- WhatTheScore Sports App http://sanjayshrestha.com/presentations/WhatTheScore.ppsx
- Get a Cab Cab Booking App https://www.behance.net/gallery/15056251/Get-a-Cab-App-Mockup-Design
- Futnotes Sports App
 https://www.behance.net/gallery/10013343/Futnotes-Mobile-UI-Development
- Inspire FM 105.1 Luton Islamic Radio
 (Google Play) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cordova.inspirefm
 (Apple App Store)https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/inspire-fm/id668434837?mt=8

UI Design Projects

- http://sanjayshrestha.com/projects/pv
- http://sanjayshrestha.com (Web)
- https://invis.io/MT6WJ1XD2(Kiosk)
- https://invis.io/US6MRJ5PX (Mobile App)
- https://invis.io/CZ6MRF4FB(Tablet)
- https://invis.io/YF6WJ7ZGC (Desktop App)

Wireframes

- https://zw4emn.axshare.com
- https://halb72.axshare.com
- https://epi8im.axshare.com

Front-end Development

- http://sanjayshrestha.com
- http://www.zeromeetings.io
- https://www.cpf.gov.sg/members
- http://sanjayshrestha.com/projects/plumbing
- http://sanjayshrestha.com/projects/rohitsoni
- http://sanjayshrestha.com/projects/skilledup

WORK HISTORY

Jan 2017 — till date

UX Architect (Full time)

Pagevamp Inc., Kathmandu, Nepal (https://pagevamp.com)

Pagevamp connects with your Facebook Page, pulls all of your information, photos and videos, to automatically build a beautiful website in seconds. No technical skills necessary!

Roles and Responsibility:

- UX Research and Analysis
- User/Stakeholder interviews
- Documentation
- Wire-framing and Prototyping
- Visual Design
- Data Analysis
- A/B Testing
- Front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery.

June 2016 – till date

UX Design Lead (Part time)

MageMojo LLC., Pittsburgh, United States (https://magemojo.com)

MageMojo is a Magento hosting provider that offers high performance, availability and security. While Magento Commerce is a fantastic piece of software, it's complexity requires significant support investment and we are here to fill that gap.

Roles and Responsibility:

- Actively engaging on UX/UI Design/Development and Usability Testing.
- Front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery.
- Graphics Design
- Website Maintenance and Events branding
- Products design

June 2014 - July 2016

UX Consultant – UX/UI Development (Part time)

Microsoft R&D Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, India(http://www.microsoft.com)

Microsoft Corporation is an American multinational corporation headquartered in Redmond, Washington, that develops, manufactures, licenses, supports and sells computer software, consumer electronics and personal computers and services. The company produces a wide range of other software for desktops and servers, and is active in areas including Internet search (with Bing), the video game industry (with the Xbox, Xbox 360 and Xbox One), the digital services market (through MSN), and mobile phones (via the Windows Phone OS).

Roles and Responsibility:

- Actively engaging on UX/UI Design/Development and Usability Testing.
- Front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery.

April 2013 - May 2014

Sr. Front-end Developer (Full time)

TQID (Top Quality Internet Development), KTM, Nepal (http://www.tgid.com)

TQID is an offshore and outsourcing based company based on Nepal. Company provides wide range of services to its customer such as Graphics Designing and Branding, Front-end and Back-end web development, Mobile app development etc. The company have around 15-25 high skilled employees and works on various tough and challenging projects across the globe.

Key accomplishment:

- Handled a dev team and was the in-touch person for any front-end related issues.
- Started the UX approach for Web and Software development.
- Started using Grunt, SASS and LESS CSS for front-end development project.
- Developing prototypes based on Bootstrapframework.
- JQuery Mobile app development.

June 2012 – March 2013

UX/UI Designer cum Front-End Developer (Full time)

Neudesic Technologies, Bangalore, India(http://www.neudesic.com)

Neudesic is a Business System Integrator for Microsoft Solutions on variety of practices like CRM, Connected Systems, Business Intelligence, Mobility, with more focus on User Experience and is a Microsoft Gold Partner & Fortune 5000 company.

Key accomplishment:

- Worked on a large project in .net platform using Bootstrap Framework and LESSCSS.
- Gained experience in AGILE development process with distributed team across the globe.
- Gained experience in various aspects of User Experience Fundamentals Requirement Analysis, User Profiling/Grouping, Personas, Task Analysis, Wireframes, Prototyping, Usability Testing

Aug 2011 – May 2012

UI Designer/Front-End Developer (Full time)

Software AndMine Pvt. Ltd., KTM, Nepal(http://www.andmine.com)

Andmine Pvt. Ltd. is a Sydney based offshore web outsourcing Full Services Digital Agency and have been providing web services since 1990.

Key accomplishment:

- Gained experience on RWD (Responsive Web Design).
- Worked on several Responsive websites using Twitter Bootstrap and coding from scratch with full browsercompatibility.
- Gained experience on Big commerce template customization.
- Started new process to design Mobile Sites/Apps based on jQuery Mobile.
- Known as a kick ass UI designer and CSS Ninja.

July 2010 - Aug 2011

UI Designer/Front-End Developer (Full time)

Crossover Web Solution, KTM, Nepal (http://www.crossoverweb.us)

Crossover is a web application development house based in Australia, US and Nepal. It is best known about solid and strong planning of work, highly experienced and energetic group, making everything possible as client wish.

Key accomplishment:

- Gained experience on HTML5/CSS3 with pixel perfect coding.
- Gained experience on WordPress template customization
- Worked on lots of EDM projects.
- Designed UIs for several popular US, AU and UK brands.
- Gained experience on customizing JQueryPlugins.

EDUCATION

2013 to present	Masters in Humanities – MA (English Literature) – Distant Learning Tribhuwan University (TU), Kathmandu, Nepal
2009-2012	Bachelor in Humanities – BA (English Literature and Social Science) Tribhuwan University (TU), Kathmandu, Nepal
2006 – 2008	10 + 2 (A level equivalent - English Literature and Social Science) Higher Secondary Education Board (HSEB), Kathmandu, Nepal

LANGUAGES

Excellent in English, Fluent in Hindi, Nepali (Native), Newari (Mother Tongue)